《权力的游戏》前情提要
你这次会说孩子的父亲是谁？
Who would you say is the father?
你
You.
我会让你怀上一个小王子
I'm going to put a prince in your belly.
女王陛下一向赏罚分明
Our queen has a keen sense of poetic justice.
如果有人能帮她除掉
What would she do for the man
叛国的弟弟们她会如何回报呢？
who rids her of her treasonous brothers?
我的名字……我真正的名字……
My name... my real name...
是伊耿·坦格利安
is Aegon Targaryen.
是真的 丹妮
It's true, Dany.
如果这是真的……
If it were true...
你生来就有铁王座的继承权
you'd have a claim to the Iron Throne.
她不喜欢你的女王 对吧？
She doesn't like your queen, does she?
她是在保护自己的家人
She's defending our family.
我也是她的家人
I'm her family, too.
别忘了这一点
Don't forget that.
m -11 -35 l -11 39 l 63 39 l 63 -35
m -86 -116 b -89 -117 -89 -117 -95 -119 l -97 -115 l -85 -105 l -116 -102 b -116 -100 -116 -98 -116 -97 l -108 -91 l -96 -91 l -116 -63 l -105 -69 l -96 -47 l -74 -63 l -77 -69 l -91 -63 l -91 -77 l -88 -80 l -66 -49 l -46 -63 l -58 -66 l -66 -74 l -49 -80 l -60 -91 l -74 -83 l -80 -91 l -77 -94 l -46 -94 l -52 -108 l -71 -105 b -69 -107 -67 -110 -66 -113 m -31 -119.875 l -33 -119 b -34 -113 -36 -107 -38 -102 l -46 -97 b -42 -93 -38 -89 -35 -85 l -44 -63 b -41 -64 -38 -65 -35 -66 l -35 -52 l -33 -47 l -27 -55 l -27 -69 l -21 -63 l -21 -69 l -19 -72 l -27 -88 l -21 -94 l -21 -99 l -27 -102 l -27 -102 l -30 -116 m -21 -113 l -21 -105 l -21 -99 l -21 -94 l -19 -85 l -19 -66 l -21 -49 l -19 -47 l -7 -52 l 26 -52 l 18 -66 l -7 -63 l -5 -69 l 6 -69 l 18 -69 l 20 -99 l -7 -94 l -7 -83 l 6 -85 l 6 -80 l -7 -77 l -7 -94 l -10 -99 l 23 -102 l 18 -116 l -10 -110 l -19 -116 m -105 -38 l -116 -41 l -110 -13 l -102 -19 l -102 -30 l -63 -33 l -55 -19 l -46 -41 l -49 -44 m -88 -33 l -91 -24 l -99 -24 l -105 -16 l -102 -13 l -85 -16 l -85 -10 l -94 -8 l -85 -16 l -102 -13 l -108 1 l -88 1 l -88 4 l -116 6 l -116 9 l -110 15 l -88 15 l -85 26 l -77 23 l -74 15 l -52 15 l -49 15 l -52 4 l -74 6 l -71 1 l -55 -2 l -60 -13 l -74 -10 l -74 -13 l -55 -16 l -63 -24 l -74 -24 l -80 -33 m -46 -41 l -38 -2 l -41 23 l -38 26 l 1 20 l 15 26 l 18 23 l 18 -8 l 20 -41 l 20 -44 l -24 -38 l -35 -41 l -35 -30 l -13 -30 l -19 -21 l -33 -19 l -33 -13 l -21 -13 l -33 6 l -33 15 l -13 -5 l -13 1 l -21 6 l -13 12 l -2 9 l -2 -8 l 9 -10 l 12 -19 l 1 -21 l -2 -27 l 9 -33 l 6 -16 l 6 -10 l 9 12 l -2 9 l -30 12 l -30 12 l -27 -2 l -27 -2 l -30 -16 l -27 -21 l -35 -41 m -126 -127 l -130 -130 l -129 38 l 34 37 l 35 -135 l -130 -131 l -127 -127 l 30 -129 l 31 32 l -124 34
最专业冰火字幕
诚意奉献
翻译 耗斯特洛夫斯卡娅子
翻译 小猴会聪明
绝境长城  the Wall
翻译 適之
翻译 LittleFireAidan
最后壁炉城Last Hearth
翻译 Oliviazqm
最专业的华语冰火资料站：        冰与火之歌中文维基
https://asoiaf.huijiwiki.com
m 31 -6 l -21 40 l 34 22 m 29 -8 l -3 -12 l -24 40
翻译 黄金镖客猫
临冬城Winterfell
翻译 雨露晋升铲屎官
翻译 熊岛莱安娜
校对 玫瑰叔
校对 Taffy的北境雪诺
校对 芹泽多摩熊
校对 龙的命根子
后期 依依Eva
监制 临冬城的狮子
监制 北落师门
联合出品
史诗图书 | 冰火中文维基 | 黑城堡奇幻微刊
Epic Books         ASOIAF.huijiwiki.com          Heichengbao
特别顾问 屈畅(ccxx)@史诗图书
君临 King's Landing
字幕组发起人 baozhenyuawabi
策划 衣柜军团
史诗图书  正统奇幻的圣殿
灰机GAME  开拓你的世界
红堡Red Keep
根据长篇小说
《冰与火之歌》 改编
原著  乔治·R·R·马丁
权力的游戏
衣柜字幕组
m -18.625 0 l -18.625 0 l 281.25 0 l 281.25 1.125 l -18.625 1.125
m -86 -116 b -89 -117 -89 -117 -95 -119 l -97 -115 l -85 -105 l -116 -102 b -116 -100 -116 -98 -116 -97 l -108 -91 l -96 -91 l -116 -63 l -105 -69 l -96 -47 l -74 -63 l -77 -69 l -91 -63 l -91 -77 l -88 -80 l -66 -49 l -46 -63 l -58 -66 l -66 -74 l -49 -80 l -60 -91 l -74 -83 l -80 -91 l -77 -94 l -46 -94 l -52 -108 l -71 -105 b -69 -107 -67 -110 -66 -113 m -31 -119.875 l -33 -119 b -34 -113 -36 -107 -38 -102 l -46 -97 b -42 -93 -38 -89 -35 -85 l -44 -63 b -41 -64 -38 -65 -35 -66 l -35 -52 l -33 -47 l -27 -55 l -27 -69 l -21 -63 l -21 -69 l -19 -72 l -27 -88 l -21 -94 l -21 -99 l -27 -102 l -27 -102 l -30 -116 m -21 -113 l -21 -105 l -21 -99 l -21 -94 l -19 -85 l -19 -66 l -21 -49 l -19 -47 l -7 -52 l 26 -52 l 18 -66 l -7 -63 l -5 -69 l 6 -69 l 18 -69 l 20 -99 l -7 -94 l -7 -83 l 6 -85 l 6 -80 l -7 -77 l -7 -94 l -10 -99 l 23 -102 l 18 -116 l -10 -110 l -19 -116 m -105 -38 l -116 -41 l -110 -13 l -102 -19 l -102 -30 l -63 -33 l -55 -19 l -46 -41 l -49 -44 m -88 -33 l -91 -24 l -99 -24 l -105 -16 l -102 -13 l -85 -16 l -85 -10 l -94 -8 l -85 -16 l -102 -13 l -108 1 l -88 1 l -88 4 l -116 6 l -116 9 l -110 15 l -88 15 l -85 26 l -77 23 l -74 15 l -52 15 l -49 15 l -52 4 l -74 6 l -71 1 l -55 -2 l -60 -13 l -74 -10 l -74 -13 l -55 -16 l -63 -24 l -74 -24 l -80 -33 m -46 -41 l -38 -2 l -41 23 l -38 26 l 1 20 l 15 26 l 18 23 l 18 -8 l 20 -41 l 20 -44 l -24 -38 l -35 -41 l -35 -30 l -13 -30 l -19 -21 l -33 -19 l -33 -13 l -21 -13 l -33 6 l -33 15 l -13 -5 l -13 1 l -21 6 l -13 12 l -2 9 l -2 -8 l 9 -10 l 12 -19 l 1 -21 l -2 -27 l 9 -33 l 6 -16 l 6 -10 l 9 12 l -2 9 l -30 12 l -30 12 l -27 -2 l -27 -2 l -30 -16 l -27 -21 l -35 -41 m -126 -127 l -130 -130 l -129 38 l 34 37 l 35 -135 l -130 -131 l -127 -127 l 30 -129 l 31 32 l -124 34
协力制作
史诗图书
Epic Books
ASOIAF.huijiwiki.com
冰火中文维基
黑城堡
EPICASTLE
第四集
最后的史塔克
The Last of the Starks
本字幕的制作目的是为了相关爱好者交流学习之用，
请在下载24小时之内删除。请勿用于任何商业用途。
乔拉·莫尔蒙
丹妮莉丝的前女王铁卫
丹妮莉丝·坦格利安
“风暴降生”“龙之母”
珊莎·史塔克
临冬城公爵夫人
席恩·葛雷乔伊
艾德·史塔克的养子
琼恩·雪诺
伊耿·坦格利安 铁王座法理继承人
艾莉亚·史塔克
布兰·史塔克
绿先知
白灵
琼恩·雪诺的冰原狼
在此 我们向我们的兄弟姐妹告别
We're here to say goodbye to our brothers and sisters.
向我们的父母告别
To our fathers and mothers.
还有我们的朋友们
To our friends.
我们的男女同胞
Our fellow men and women
放下了彼此间的隔阂
who set aside their differences...
并肩作战
to fight together...
共同牺牲
and die together
塔斯的布蕾妮
爵士 “美人”
詹姆·兰尼斯特
“弑君者”
其他人才得以继续生存
so that others might live.
这世上所有人
Everyone in this world
都欠他们一份无法偿还的债
owes them a debt that can never be repaid.
永远铭记他们的事迹
It is our duty and our honor
是我们的责任和荣耀
to keep them alive in memory...
让我们的子孙后代
for those who come after us...
以及后代的后代
and those who come after them...
永世不忘 直到世界尽头
for as long as men draw breath.
他们是守护王国的坚盾
They were the shields that guarded the realms of men.
桑铎·克里冈
“猎狗”
戴佛斯·席渥斯
“洋葱骑士”
他们的忠勇后无来者
And we shall never see their like again.
弥桑黛
丹妮莉丝的翻译和顾问
提利昂·兰尼斯特
“小恶魔” 丹妮莉丝的女王之手
贝里·唐德利恩
“闪电大王”
山姆威尔·塔利
守夜人
艾迪森·托勒特
“忧郁的艾迪” 前守夜人指挥官
莱安娜·莫尔蒙
前熊岛伯爵夫人
灰虫子
无垢者指挥官
祝你健康
To your health.
詹德利
“大牛” 劳勃国王的私生子
你看见艾莉亚了吗？
Have you seen Arya?
葬礼的气味还没散掉
You can still smell the burning bodies,
你就在琢磨这种事
and that's where your head is at.
- 我只是想感谢她—— - 你当然很感激
- I just want to thank her for-- - I'm sure you do.
拜托 不是为了那事
Look, it's not about that.
当然是为了那事 你个蠢货
Of course it's about that, you twat.
为什么不呢？
Why shouldn't it be?
尸鬼大军都死了 但你还活着
The dead are dead. You're not.
詹德利
Gendry.
是这个名字 对吧？
That's right, isn't it?
是的 陛下
Yes, Your Grace.
你是劳勃·拜拉席恩的儿子
You're Robert Baratheon's son.
你可知道他夺走了我父亲的王位
You are aware he took my family's throne
还试图杀死我？
and tried to have me murdered?
他死后我才知道他是我父亲
I didn't even know he was my father until after he was dead.
没错 他死了
Yes, he's dead.
他的兄弟们也是
His brothers are too.
所以现在谁是风息堡公爵了？
So who's Lord of Storm's End now?
我不知道 陛下
I don't know, Your Grace.
有人知道吗？
Does anyone?
吉莉
山姆的爱人
我觉得你应该成为风息堡公爵
I think you should be Lord of Storm's End.
我不能继任 我是私生子
I can't be. I'm a bastard.
不 你是风息堡公爵 詹德利·拜拉席恩
No, you are Lord Gendry Baratheon of Storm's End,
劳勃·拜拉席恩的合法子嗣
the lawful son of Robert Baratheon.
因为这是我的旨意
Because that is what I have made you.
敬风息堡公爵 詹德利·拜拉席恩
To Lord Gendry Baratheon of Storm's End.
敬詹德利！
To Gendry!
詹德利公爵！
Lord Gendry!
詹德利！
Gendry!
- 詹德利！ - 詹德利！
- Gendry! - Gendry!
詹德利公爵！
Lord Gendry!
詹德利！
Gendry!
还挺容易 是吧？
That's easy, isn't it?
- 既给英雄合理封赏 - 呃 等等
- A fitting reward for a hero. - Uh, hold on.
- 又得到一位永远忠诚的风息堡公爵
And a Lord of Storm's End who will be forever loyal to you.
- 过来吧 大人 - 看见没？
- Come, my lord. - See?
你不是唯一一个聪明人
You're not the only one who's clever.
我得再下去拿一桶
I have to go down and get another barrel.
我们打赢了尸鬼 还能活着讨论这事
We fought dead things and lived to talk about it.
现在不喝点的话 还等什么时候？
If this isn't the time to drink, when is?
上次我见到她的时候
The last time I saw her,
我告诉她再见面时一定会杀了她
I told her I'd kill her if I ever saw her again.
- 你一定有你的理由 - 我确实有
- I'm sure you had your reasons. - I did.
- 现在也有 - 所以你杀了她吗？
- I do. - So did you?
没给我机会
Never got the chance.
她自己了断了
She did it to herself.
也有可能是她的神了结了她
Or her god did it to her.
光之王
Lord of Light.
我们参与着他的游戏 为他战斗并且取得胜利
We play his game for him, we fight his war and win,
然后
and then
他就滚蛋了
he fucks off.
没有神迹 也没有赐福 鬼知道他到底想要什么？
No signs, no blessings. Who knows what he wants?
还是不要考虑这种事了
I don't imagine thinking about that subject
你才能开心起来
will leave you any happier than before.
要是我原本就不想开心呢？
And what if I'm not trying to be happy?
那算你走运
Then you're in luck.
我们纵然打败了异鬼
We may have defeated them,
但还得和自己人斗
but we still have us to contend with.
谢谢 我感觉好多了
Thank you. I feel much better.
再来点麦酒！
More ale!
这东西真精巧
This is clever.
比我给你设计的鞍座还强
Even better than the saddle I designed for you.
这是120年前 戴伦·坦格利安
It's the same as the one Daeron Targaryen built
为他残废的侄子打造的同款
for his crippled nephew 120 years ago.
我很中意那款
I liked that one.
你比任何人都了解历史
You know our history better than anyone.
要成为临冬城公爵的话这些知识会很有用
That will be useful as Lord of Winterfell.
我不是临冬城公爵
I'm not Lord of Winterfell.
但你是奈德·史塔克唯一在世的婚生儿子
You're the only surviving trueborn son of Ned Stark.
你不想继承这个爵位
You don't want it.
我什么都不想了
I don't really want anymore.
我真嫉妒你
I envy you.
你没必要嫉妒我
You shouldn't envy me.
我基本上活在过去
Mostly I live in the past.
- 全干了 - 赶紧的
- All of it. - Go on.
- 不行 干不了 - 赶紧的 相信你可以
- No, not in one go. - Go on. I believe in you.
托蒙德
“巨人克星”
为胜利而狂欢
We have to celebrate our victory.
醉了狂吐可不算是狂欢
Vomiting is not celebrating.
不 也算
Yes, it is.
来！
Ah!
敬龙女王！
To the Dragon Queen!
敬艾莉亚·史塔克 临冬城的英雄！
To Arya Stark, the hero of Winterfell!
- 喝！喝！喝！喝！ - 干了！
- Rah! Rah! Rah! Rah! - Drink!
我可没醉！
I'm fine!
到你了
Your turn.
呃……
Um...
你是家中独生子女
You are an only child.
波德瑞克·派恩
布蕾妮的侍从
- 我以前告诉过你 - 你可没
- I told you I was. - You didn't.
- 我说过了 - 我自己猜的
- I did. - I surmised it.
喝吧
Drink.
再来一次
Go again.
为什么他就可以再来一次？
Why does he get to go again?
因为规矩是我定的
Because it's my game.
你跟蓝礼·拜拉席恩共舞过
You have danced with Renly Baratheon.
我没说过
No.
继续喝吧
Drink.
换种方式说！
The other way around!
我亲眼看见过他骑着那大家伙
I saw him riding that thing.
- 我们都见过 - 不 不是
- We all did. - No. No.
是我亲眼看见他骑着那大家伙的
I saw him riding that thing.
- 行 是你看见的 - 当然是我
- That's right, you did. - I did.
我们愿意跟随他
That's why we all agreed to follow him.
正因为他是这样的汉子
That's the kind of man he is.
他虽然有点小……
He's little...
……但是很强大
...but he's strong.
强大到令敌人折服
Strong enough to befriend an enemy
甚至因此被杀！
and get murdered for it!
大多数人被杀后
Most people get bloody murdered,
就躺那儿不动了
they stay that way.
他可不一样
Not this one.
可别说了 这事我也做不了主啊
Yeah, I didn't have much say in that.
啊哈！他凯旋而归 不断战斗
Ah! He comes back and keeps fighting.
从这出发 打到长城以北 又打回这里
Here, north of the Wall, and then back here again.
他一直战斗 勇往无前
He keeps fighting. He keeps fighting.
他爬上龙背战斗
He climbed on a fucking dragon and fought.
什么人才会爬到龙背上？
What kind of person climbs on a fucking dragon?
不是个疯子就是王者！
A madman or a king!
- 喝吧 - 继续喝吧
- Drink. - Drink.
喝
Drink.
瓦里斯
“八爪蜘蛛”
猜错了！
Wrong!
错了错了错了 你喝！
Wrong, wrong, wrong! Drink!
嗯！
Mm!
珊莎不是你第一任妻子
You were married. Before Sansa.
喝
Drink.
你爱喝葡萄酒 但你更爱麦芽酒！
You're drinking wine, but you prefer ale!
才不是！
No!
你是个处女
You're a virgin.
这是对当前的陈述
That's a statement about the present.
从过去 直到现在
At no point in the past, up until this very moment,
你都没和男人同过床
have you slept with a man.
包括女人
Or a woman.
我要小个便
I have to piss.
我们成功了！ 我们直面那些寒冰怪物
We did it! We faced those icy fucks.
直视它们的蓝眼睛
Looked right into their blue eyes,
最后我们还活了下来
and here we are.
现在 你们这些软蛋还敢在老子头上撒野？
Now, which one of you cowards shit in my pants?
失陪一下
Please pardon me for a moment.
干了这杯！
Drink it!
到了最后
And after all that,
这混蛋竟然来了北边 还从我身边夺走了她
this fucker comes north and takes her from me.
就这样被抢走了
Just takes her, like that.
我是认真的 克里冈
I mean it, Clegane.
我的心伤透了
My heart is broken.
别挨着老子
Don't touch me.
你可以挨着我
You can touch me.
我可不怕你们这些野人
I'm not afraid of wildlings.
也许你应该怕的
Maybe you should be.
就这样吧 克里冈
Well, Clegane...
是时候忘记悲伤
it's time to drown our sorrows.
我的酒还没喝完
I'm not done with my drink.
现在喝完了吗？
Are you ready now?
我的酒在这
This is my drink.
够了！
All right!
她本来可以让你享受一段欢愉时光
She could have made you happy, for a little while.
世界上只有一件事情可以让我开心
There's only one thing that'll make me happy.
是什么？
And what's that?
关你屁事
That's my fucking business.
以前的你甚至不敢直视我
Used to be you couldn't look at me.
那是很久以前了
That was a long time ago.
那以后 我经历的事情比你更可怕
I've seen much worse than you since then.
嗯 有所耳闻
Yes, I've heard.
听说你被强暴了
Heard you were broken in.
而且他很粗暴
Heard you were broken in rough.
最后他罪有应得
And he got what he deserved.
我亲手做的
I gave it to him.
怎样？
How?
猎狗
Hounds.
你变了 小小鸟
You've changed, Little Bird.
如果你跟我一起离开君临
None of it would have happened
这些就都不会发生
if you'd left King's Landing with me.
没有小指头 没有拉姆斯……
No Littlefinger, no Ramsay...
什么事都不会有
none of it.
没有小指头 拉姆斯和其他人
Without Littlefinger, and Ramsay and the rest,
我一辈子都会是那只小小鸟
I would have stayed a Little Bird all my life.
别射我
Don't shoot.
现在是深夜 又这么冷 所有人都在庆祝
It's nighttime, it's freezing, and everyone's celebrating.
你应该去和大家一起庆祝
You should be celebrating with them.
我在庆祝呀
I am celebrating.
嗯 我也是
Yeah, I am too.
我不再是詹德利·河文了
I'm not Gendry Rivers anymore.
而是詹德利·拜拉席恩 风息堡公爵
I'm Gendry Baratheon, Lord of Storm's End.
女王赐给我的
By order of the queen.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
我不知道怎么做一个领主
I don't know how to be lord of anything.
我甚至不太会用叉子
I hardly know how to use a fork.
我只知道你很美
All I know is that you're beautiful,
我爱你
and I love you,
如果你不和我在一起
and none of it will be worth anything
这些就都没有意义了
if you're not with me.
所以 和我在一起吧
So be with me.
做我的妻子 风息堡的公爵夫人
Be my wife. Be the Lady of Storm's End.
你会是一个很好的领主
You'll be a wonderful lord,
不管哪位淑女小姐嫁给你 那都是她的福气
and any lady would be lucky to have you.
但我不是一个淑女
But I'm not a lady.
从来都不是
I never have been.
那不是我
That's not me.
你没喝
You didn't drink.
- 我没喝？- 在游戏时
- I didn't drink? - In the game.
- 我喝了 - 还差一杯 这可是多恩的酒
- I drank. - In the game. This is Dornish.
这只是喝酒 不是什么游戏
This is not the game. This is only drinking.
随便你
Suit yourself.
你屋里挺暖和啊
You keep it warm enough in here.
这是我到北境后最先学会的事
It's the first thing I learnt when I came to the North.
让火一直烧着
Keep your fire going.
每次离开房间都要多添些柴
Every time you leave the room, put more wood on.
你可真是勤劳有担当
That's very diligent. Very responsible.
- 滚 - 你知道我到北境后
- Piss off. - You know the first thing
明白的第一件事是什么吗？
I learned in the North?
我他妈恨透了北境
I hate the fucking North.
你会慢慢喜欢的
It grows on you.
我才不想喜欢上什么
I don't want things growing on me.
那巨人克星托蒙德呢？
How about Tormund Giantsbane?
你喜欢上他了吗？
Has he grown on you?
你离开后他很难过
He was very sad when you left.
听起来你是吃醋了
You sound quite jealous.
不然呢？
I do, don't I?
这里可热死了
It's bloody hot in here.
行吧 手拿开
Oh, move aside.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
脱你衣服啊
I'm taking your shirt off.
我从没和骑士睡过
I've never slept with a knight before.
我没和任何人睡过
I've never slept with anyone before.
那你得喝酒 这是规矩
Then you have to drink. Those are the rules.
我跟你说了——
I told you--
你喝醉了吗？
Are you drunk?
没
No.
有一点点
Only a little.
我不太了解乔拉爵士……
I didn't know Ser Jorah well...
但我知道一点
but I know this.
如果他能选择死亡的方式
If he could have chosen a way to die,
一定会选择为你战死
it would have been protecting you.
他爱我
He loved me.
但我不能爱他
And I couldn't love him back.
不能像他想要的那样
Not the way he wanted.
不能像我爱你一样
Not the way I love you.
这样可以吗？
Is that all right?
我希望你没告诉我真相
I wish you'd never told me.
如果我不知道 现在就会很开心了
If I didn't know, I'd be happy right now.
我试着忘记
I try to forget.
今晚我忘记了一会儿
Tonight I did for a while,
然后我看到他们围在你身边
and then I saw them gathered around you.
还有他们看你的眼神
I saw the way they looked at you.
我知道那种眼神
I know that look.
以前很多人那样看过我 但不是在这儿
So many people have looked at me that way, but never here.
在这片大陆上 从来没有过
Never on this side of the sea.
我说过我不想要铁王座
I told you I don't want it.
他们不在乎你想不想要
It doesn't matter what you want.
之前你也不想当北境之王
You didn't want to be King in the North.
如果他们要求你称王
What happens when they demand you press your claim,
从我手上夺走王位呢？
and take what is mine?
我会拒绝的
I'll refuse.
你是我的女王 我不知道我还能说些什么
You are my queen. I don't know what else I can say.
你可以守口如瓶
You can say nothing.
永远不跟任何人说
To anyone, ever.
永远不告诉他们你的真实身份
Never tell them who you really are.
让你的弟弟和山姆威尔·塔利发誓保密
Swear your brother and Samwell Tarly to secrecy,
绝不说出去
and tell no one else.
不然事情传出去
Or it will take on a life of its own
你根本无法控制
and you won't be able to control it
更不知道会有什么影响
or what it does to people.
不管你下跪称臣多少次
No matter how many times you bend the knee,
你再怎么发誓 都无济于事
no matter what you swear.
我希望我们还像从前那样
I want it to be the way it was between us.
我必须告诉珊莎和艾莉亚
I have to tell Sansa and Arya.
珊莎会想让我走 然后你坐上铁王座
Sansa will want to see me gone and you on the Iron Throne.
她不会的
She won't.
她不是和你一起长大的那个女孩了
She's not the girl you grew up with.
在她目睹了这么多
Not after what she's seen,
遭受过这么多之后 早就不是了
not after what they've done to her.
我应该告诉她们真相
I owe them the truth.
即使这会毁掉我们俩？
Even if the truth destroys us?
- 不会的 - 不 它会的
- It won't. - It will.
我从未因为任何事求过别人……
I've never begged for anything...
但是我现在求你
but I'm begging you.
不要这么做 拜托了
Don't do this. Please.
你是我的女王
You are my queen.
这是不会改变的
Nothing will change that.
她们是我的家人
And they are my family.
我们可以一起生活
We can live together.
的确可以
We can.
我也告诉你该怎么做了
I've just told you how.
无垢者损失了半数
Half are gone.
北境军队也是
The Northmen as well.
黄金团已经到达君临
And the Golden Company has arrived in King's Landing,
多亏了葛雷乔伊的舰队
courtesy of the Greyjoy fleet.
双方实力已经均等得令人烦恼了
The balance has grown distressingly even.
当人们发现我们为他们做了什么
When the people find out what we have done for them,
我们拯救了他们——
that we saved them--
瑟曦会确保人们不会相信的
Cersei will make sure they don't believe it.
我们会痛击她
We will hit her hard.
我们必将她连根拔起 铲除殆尽
We will rip her out root and stem.
这次会议的议题是怎么除掉瑟曦
The objective here is to remove Cersei
同时不毁掉君临
without destroying King's Landing.
谢天谢地 她的盟友在弃她而去
Thankfully,she's losing allies by the day.
亚拉·葛雷乔伊已经以女王之名
Yara Greyjoy has retaken the Iron Islands
重新夺回铁群岛
in her queen's name.
多恩的新亲王也承诺他会提供援助
The new Prince of Dorne pledges his support.
不管有多少贵族对瑟曦倒戈相向
No matter how many lords turn against her,
只要她还坐在铁王座上
as long as she sits on the Iron Throne,
她就可以自称是七大王国的女王
she can call herself Queen of the Seven Kingdoms.
我们得拿下都城
We need the capital.
我见过君临的人们
I watched the people of King's Landing
在极度饥饿下反抗他们的国王
rebel against their king when they were hungry,
这还是在凛冬来临之前的事情
and that was before winter began.
给他们这个机会 他们会推翻瑟曦
Give them the opportunity and they will cast Cersei aside.
我们出军包围整座城
We'll surround the city.
如果铁舰队试图往城里运输食物
If the Iron Fleet tries to ferry in more food,
龙可以消灭他们
the dragons will destroy them.
如果兰尼斯特军队和黄金团发动进攻
If the Lannisters and the Golden Company attack,
我们会在战场上打败他们
we'll defeat them in the field.
一旦人们意识到我们只视瑟曦为敌人
Once the people see that Cersei is our only enemy,
她的统治就结束了
her reign is over.
那好吧
All right.
我们剩下的人马都筋疲力竭
The men we have left are exhausted.
大部分都受了伤
Many of them are wounded.
如果能给他们时间休息恢复
They'll fight better if they have time to
他们能更好地打下一场仗
rest and recuperate.
你建议恢复多久？
How long do you suggest?
我不确定
I can't say for certain,
得和长官们聊聊才知道
not without talking to the officers.
我来到北境和你并肩作战
I came north to fight alongside you
这场战争也让我损失惨重
at great cost to my armies and myself.
现在该是你回报我的时候
Now that the time has come to reciprocate,
你却想推迟
you want to postpone.
那不仅是我们的人民 也是您的
It's not just our people.It's yours.
您想让他们没准备好
You want to throw them into a war
就上战场？
they're not ready to fight?
我给敌人的准备时间越长
The longer I leave my enemies alone,
他们就会越强大
the stronger they become.
北境会向七大王国的女王
The Northern forces will honor their promises
遵守他们的承诺
and their allegiance
并保持忠诚
to the Queen of the Seven Kingdoms.
您的命令 我们必将服从
What you command, we will obey.
那么……
So...
既然我们达成了一致……
if all are in agreement...
琼恩和戴佛斯爵士沿着国王大道
Jon and Ser Davos will ride down the Kingsroad
率领北境军队
with the Northern troops
以及多斯拉克人和无垢者残部的多数南下
and the bulk of the remaining Dothraki and Unsullied.
我们小部分人先骑马到白港
A smaller group of us will ride to White Harbor,
然后坐船前往龙石岛
and sail from there to Dragonstone
女王和她的龙与我们一路
with our queen and her dragons accompanying us from above.
詹姆爵士选择留在这里
Ser Jaime has chosen to remain here,
作为临冬城公爵夫人的客人
as a guest of the Lady of Winterfell.
我们已经打赢了生死之战
We have won the Great War.
现在 我们将拿下最后一战
Now we will win the Last War.
从此七国之内
In all Seven Kingdoms,
在正统的女王统治下人们将不会生活在
men will live without fear and cruelty
恐惧和残忍的压迫之中
under their rightful queen.
我们得聊聊
We need a word.
你们要知道 多亏了她 不然我们都会死
You understand we'd all be dead if not for her.
都会变成向君临进军的死尸
We'd be corpses marching down to King's Landing.
艾莉亚才是杀掉夜王的人
Arya's the one that killed the Night King.
她的人为了保护临冬城送了命——
Her men gave their lives defending Winterfell--
我们永远不会忘记他们
And we will never forget them.
但这并不意味着我想向她俯首称臣——
That doesn't mean that I want to kneel to someone who--
我曾发誓我自己和北境都效忠于她的大业
I swore myself and the North to her cause.
我尊重你的决定
I respect that.
你真尊重？
You respect it?
我们之前需要她
We needed her.
需要她的军队和龙
We needed her army, her dragons.
你做了正确的选择
You did the right thing.
而我们现在正确的做法就是告诉你
And we're doing the right thing telling you
我们不相信你的女王
we don't trust your queen.
- 你还不了解她 - 我永远都不会了解她
- You don't know her yet. - I'll never know her.
她不是我们中的一员
She's not one of us.
如果你只相信和你一起长大的人
If you only trust the people you grew up with,
你没法结交很多的盟友
you won't make many allies.
那有什么关系
That's all right.
我不需要那么多盟友
I don't need many allies.
- 艾莉亚…… - 我们是一家人
- Arya... - We're family.
我们四个
The four of us.
是最后的史塔克
The last of the Starks.
我从来都不是史塔克家族的人
I've never been a Stark.
你是
You are.
你跟我们一样 都是奈德·史塔克的孩子
You're just as much Ned Stark's child as any of us.
你是我的哥哥
You're my brother.
不是同父异母的哥哥或是私生子哥哥
Not my half-brother or my bastard brother.
而是我的哥哥
My brother.
说不说看你了
It's your choice.
我要告诉你们一件事
I need to tell you something.
但是你们得发誓不会告诉任何人
But you have to swear you'll never tell another soul.
什么事？
What is it?
你得先发誓 我才能告诉你
You have to swear it,before I tell you.
如果我连秘密是什么还不知道
How can I promise to keep a secret
我怎么能发誓？
if I don't even know what it is?
因为我们是一家人
Because we're family.
发誓
Swear it.
我发誓
I swear it.
我也发誓
告诉她们吧
Tell them.
所以她会跟你一起留下？
So she's going to stay here with you?
她曾发誓会保护史塔克家的姑娘们 所以……
She's sworn to protect the Stark girls, so...
尽管冷嘲热讽吧
Say something snide.
我很高兴
I'm happy.
看到你开心 我也替你高兴
I'm happy that you're happy.
看到你终于也得爬上去干那事 我高兴得不得了
I'm happy that you'll finally have to climb for it.
你知道我等着讲高个子的荤段子等了多久吗？
Do you know how long I've waited to tell tall-person jokes?
敬攀上高峰
To climbing mountains.
- 她下面是什么样子？ - 什么？
- What's she like down there? - What?
不关你事
That's not your concern.
我已经好几年没碰女人了
I haven't been with a woman for years.
- 透露一点嘛  - 你个狗玩东西
- Give me a morsel. - You're a dog.
我是小恶魔 我就是要知道
I am the Imp, and I demand to know.
我知道你干了她
I knew you were fucking her.
波隆
黑水河骑士
一对高个 金发的上流社会人士
A pair of tall, blond toffs.
你肯定觉得像在照镜子吧
Must be like looking in the mirror.
黑水河的波隆爵士
Ser Bronn of the Blackwater.
不带酒就来了？
Where's your drink?
你来——你来北境做什么？
What are you--What are you doing up North?
你拿着那个要干嘛？
What are you doing with that?
噢 这个？
Oh, this?
这是给你们准备的
This is for you.
你俩都有份
For both of you.
你不是该待在南方么
You're supposed to be south.
你们两兄弟是一对镀金的傻屌
You boys are a pair of gold-plated cunts.
- 你们知道吗？  - 这很没礼貌啊
- Do you know that? - That's a bit rude.
这些年我都在铲你们兰尼斯特家族的臭屎
Year after year, I've shoveled Lannister shit,
- 我得到了什么值得夸耀的呢？ - 多亏我 你成了骑士
- and what do I have to show? - You're a knight, thanks to me.
多亏了我自己 而且那个头衔跟你哥蛋蛋上的
Thanks to me. And that title's worth as much
一根金色屌毛一样不值钱
as a blond hair from your brother's ballsack.
价值在于人们相信——
Power resides where men believe--
你闭嘴
Shut your mouth.
- 我只是想—— - 我从来没揍过侏儒
- I'm just trying-- - I've never hit a dwarf before,
但是你再逼逼一句 我就抽你
but say another word and I will belt you.
你看 我不信你会这样做 毕竟——
See, I don't believe you'd do that, after all--
你这个独臂杂种
You couldn't do it on your best day,
在你全盛时期也打不过我
you one-handed fuck.
更何况那已经是很久以前了
And your best days are long gone.
你把我的鼻子打破了！
You broke my nose!
- 我没有打破你的鼻子  - 你怎么知道？
- I did not break your nose. - How do you know?
因为我像你这么高的时候就已经打破别人鼻子了
Because I've been breaking noses since I was your size,
我知道该是什么声儿 现在给我听着
and I know what it sounds like. Now listen.
你们老姐许诺给我奔流城
Your sister offered me Riverrun.
漂亮的大城堡 肥沃的土地
Nice big castle, good lands,
很多言听计从的农民
plenty of peasants who do what they're told.
- 而你相信瑟曦—— - 我当时看到那几只龙的时候
- And you trust Cersei— - I knew your sister was dead
就知道你们老姐死定了
the second I saw those dragons.
现在 或许你们的军队被虐成渣了
Now, your army may be torn to shit,
但我还是赌你们的龙女王赢
but I'd still bet on your Dragon Queen to win.
正好我是个赌徒
And it just so happens I'm a betting man.
如果瑟曦死了 她就不能兑现承诺了
If Cersei's dead, she can't pay up.
嗯 这酒不错 当然 如果龙女王的首相暴毙了
Mmm, that's good. Of course, the odds change
双方输赢的几率就变了
if the Dragon Queen's Hand turns up dead.
她的几个大将可能会一个接一个被干掉
Maybe a few of her top generals get picked off one by one.
- 突然…… - 我能说两句吗？
- All of a sudden… - May I speak?
当然 你只有死了才能闭嘴
Why not? Only death will shut you up.
你还记得我们很久以前达成的协议吗？
We made a deal long ago. Do you remember?
如果有人出钱
If anyone offered me money
让我杀你 你会付我双倍
to kill you, you'd pay me double.
奔流城的双倍是什么？
What's double Riverrun?
高庭
Highgarden.
你可以成为河湾地的领主
You could be Lord of the Reach.
- 高庭？你疯了吗？ - 总比让我们死好
- Highgarden? Are you mad? - It's better than being dead.
他不会杀我们的
He's not going to kill us.
否则不会跟我们说这么多——
He wouldn't be talking to us if--
看来
The way I see it,
我只需要让一个兰尼斯特兄弟活着
I only need one of the Lannister brothers alive.
高庭不能属于一个杀手
Highgarden will never belong to a cutthroat.
不能？ 让你们家族繁荣起来的
No? Who were your ancestors,
祖先是什么人？
the ones who made your family rich?
穿着丝绸的花哨小伙子？
Fancy lads in silk?
他们也不过是杀手
They were fucking cutthroats.
所有的大家族都是这么发展起来的 不是吗？
That's how all the great houses started, isn't it?
靠一个擅长杀人的混蛋白手起家
With a hard bastard who was good at killing people.
杀几百个人 他们封你作领主
Kill a few hundred people, they make you a lord.
杀几千个人 他们拥戴你当王
Kill a few thousand, they make you king.
然后你的傻屌后代们就可以用他们的傻屌方式
And then all your cocksucking grandsons can ruin the family
毁了这个家族
with their cocksucking ways.
高庭
Highgarden.
你向我保证
Give me your word.
我向你保证
You have my word.
没拿下君临之前说这些都没有意义
None of this means a thing until we take King's Landing.
我们明早启程 进军南方
We ride south in the morning.
我们需要一个对君临防卫情况
We could use an officer
了如指掌的人 作我们的军官
with knowledge of the city's defenses.
噢 算了吧
Oh, no.
不了 我打仗的日子已经结束了
No, my fighting days are done.
但我杀人的日子还没结束 你们懂了吗
But I still got a few killing days left, you hear me?
等战争结束了我会来找你们
I'll come find you when the war is done.
别在那之前死了
Till then, don't die.
我日
For fuck's sake.
你一个人？
On your own?
现在不是了
Not anymore.
我不喜欢热闹
I don't like crowds.
我也是
Me neither.
为什么？他们现在都很喜欢你
Why not? They all love you now.
你是大英雄
You're the big hero.
我不喜欢当英雄
Don't like heroes.
用匕首刺死那个长角的混蛋肯定很爽吧
It must have felt good sticking a knife in that horned fucker.
比死感觉好一点
Felt better than dying.
你打算去君临？
You're heading to King's Landing?
我还有些事没做了断
I have some unfinished business.
我也是
Me too.
我没准备回来
I don't plan on coming back.
我也是
Neither do I.
如果我受伤了 你打算又让我自己等死吗？
Gonna leave me to die again if I get hurt?
有可能
Probably.
雷哥
丹妮莉丝的绿龙
卓耿
丹妮莉丝的黑龙
夫人
My lady.
标准的回答应该是“大人”
"My lord" is the standard response.
为什么是她？
Why her?
你知道她爱你哥哥
You know she loves your brother.
那并不意味着她能成为一个好的女王
That doesn't mean she'll be a good queen.
你似乎打定主意就是要不喜欢她
You seem determined to dislike her.
铁王座和北境
A good relationship
维持良好的关系
between the Iron Throne and the North
一直都是以往任何和平 繁荣
has been the core of every peaceful,
统治的关键
prosperous reign we've ever known.
琼恩会成为北境守护
Jon will be Warden of the North,
所以 应该会维持良好关系吧
so a good relationship seems likely.
我认为今后他不会在这里呆太久
I don't expect him to spend much time here going forward.
好吧 我想这得由他自己决定
Well, I suppose that's up to him.
珊莎 看着我
Sansa, look at me.
要是琼恩待在首都
With Jon in the capital,
你就会成为北境的真正掌权者
you'll be the true power in the North.
如果我今天离开这里的时候可以确信
I'd feel much better about the future
你和丹妮莉丝是盟友
if I left here today believing
我会对未来更有信心
that you and Daenerys were allies.
你在担心什么？ 琼恩会带着我们的军队一起走
What are you worried about? Jon's taking our army with him.
你们的女王还拥有她的龙
Your queen still has her dragons--
她也是你的女王
She's your queen too.
你不必做她的朋友
You don't have to be her friend.
但你为什么非得招惹她呢？
But why provoke her?
这对你的家族有什么好处呢？
How is that in the best interest of your family,
- 对北境  或是对——？ - 你害怕她
- or the North, or--? - You're afraid of her.
每一位优秀的统治者都需要让臣民有敬畏之心
Every good ruler needs to inspire a bit of fear.
我不想让琼恩南下君临
I don't want Jon to go down there.
我们家族的男人去了君临都没好事
The men in my family don't do well in the capital.
对 可你的哥哥告诉过我
No, but as your brother once told me,
他不是史塔克家族的人
he's not a Stark.
你还好吗？
Are you all right?
你看到了 她的臣民爱戴她
Her people love her, you've seen that.
你看到了他们如何为她战斗
You've seen how they fight for her.
她想让世界变得更好
She wants to make the world a better place.
我相信她
I believe in her.
提利昂
Tyrion.
如果还有其他人呢？
What if there's someone else?
其他更好的人选呢？
Someone better?
你不打算骑龙去南方吗？
You're not gonna ride the dragon south?
就骑马去
Just a horse.
雷哥需要养伤
Rhaegal needs to heal.
我不能成为他的负担
He doesn't need me weighing him down.
你只有两只跳蚤那么重
You weigh as much as two fleas fucking.
我要带自由民回家了
I'm taking the Free Folk home.
我们受够了南方
We've had enough of the south.
这儿的女人不喜欢我
The women down here don't like me.
你知道的 这就是北方
This is the North, you know.
欢迎自由民留在这儿
And the Free Folk are welcome to stay.
这儿不是家
It isn't home.
我们需要能游荡的空间
We need room to wander.
等冬天的暴风雪一停
I'll take them back through Castle Black
我就带他们穿过黑城堡
as soon as the winter storms pass.
回到我们的地盘
Back where we belong.
也是它的地盘
It's where he belongs too.
冰原狼不适合待在南方
A direwolf has no place in the south.
你能带上它吗？
Will you take him with you?
它在那儿会更自在些
He'll be happier up there.
你也会的
So would you.
我真希望能和你一起去
I wish I was going with you.
那么就 永别了
This is farewell, then.
谁知道呢
You never know.
你现在是个北方人了
You've got the North in you.
我是说真正的北方人
The real North.
好吧 黑夜越来越长
Yes, well, the nights have been getting longer
在旧镇又没有什么可做的
and there wasn't that much to do in Oldtown.
总不能老看书吧 所以我们——
There's only so many books a person can read, so we--
山姆 我确定他知道这是怎么发生的
I'm sure he knows how it happens, Sam.
如果是个男孩 我们想叫他琼恩
If it's a boy, we want to name him Jon.
我希望是个女孩
I hope it's a girl.
你是我最好的朋友
You're the best friend I ever had.
你也是 山姆
You too, Sam.
想想过去的二十年
Think of the past 20 years.
战争 谋杀 痛苦
The war, the murder, the misery.
全都是因为劳勃·拜拉席恩爱上一个
All of it because Robert Baratheon loved someone
不爱他的人
who didn't love him back.
还有多少人知道？
How many others know?
加上咱俩？八个
Including us? Eight.
好吧 这不再是个秘密了
Well, then it's not a secret anymore.
而是信息
It's information.
如果现在个别人知道了 很快就会有几百人知道
If a handful of people know now, hundreds will know soon.
接着会发生什么？
Then what happens?
她会失去北境
She loses the North.
她会失去谷地 珊莎保准会做到
She loses the Vale, Sansa will make sure of that.
不 比这更糟
No, it's worse than that.
他的继承顺位更靠前
He has the better claim to the throne.
他不想要王位
He doesn't want the throne.
他的想法并不重要
I'm not sure it matters what he wants.
事实是 他是人心所向的
The fact is, people are drawn to him.
野人 北境人
Wildlings, Northmen.
他是战争中的英雄
He's a war hero.
他爱我们的女王
He loves our queen.
她也爱他
And she loves him.
如果我们让他们结婚 他们可以共同统治
If we marry them, they could rule together.
但她是他的姑妈
She's his aunt.
这可从来阻止不了一位坦格利安人
That never stopped a Targaryen before.
不 可琼恩在临冬城长大
No, but Jon grew up in Winterfell.
在北境 娶自己的姑妈正常吗？
Is marrying your aunt common in the North?
你比我更了解我们的女王
You know our queen better than I do.
你觉得她想分享王座吗？
Do you think she wants to share the throne?
她可不喜欢她的权威被质疑
She does not like to have her authority questioned.
这是她和每位
Something she has in common
君王的共同点
with every monarch who ever lived.
我担心她的精神状态
I worry about her state of mind.
我们是女王的顾问
We are advisors to the queen.
担心她的精神状态是我们的职责
Worrying about her state of mind is our job.
我们仍需拿下君临
We still have to take King's Landing.
也许瑟曦会赢 然后把我们都杀了
Maybe Cersei will win and kill us all.
这倒能解决我们的问题
That would solve our problems.
攸伦·葛雷乔伊
铁群岛之王
到小船上去 快！
Get to the skiff. Now!
矛！
Spears!
他们又来了！
They're coming round again!
上！
Go!
明白！
Clear!
守住阵地！
Man your stations!
不！
No!
- 上！上！ - 明白！
- Go! Go! - Clear!
弥桑黛？
Missandei?
弥桑黛！
Missandei!
那么 我们的消息反响很好 ？
Our message was well-received, then?
您的人民听说了篡夺者要来
Your people have heard the Usurper is coming.
他们很感激您对他们的保护
They are grateful for your protection
瑟曦·兰尼斯特
铁王座上的女王
感激您让他们进入红堡的城墙之内
within the walls of the Red Keep.
科本
被剥夺项链的学士 瑟曦的女王之手
你确定龙死了？
You're certain about the dragon?
我看着它没入海浪
I saw it sink beneath the waves.
那肯定很壮观
That must have been glorious.
这都属于您 我的女王
The glory is yours, my queen.
等战争胜利 狮子将统治大陆
When the war is won, the Lion shall rule the land,
海怪将会统治大海
the Kraken shall rule the sea...
而我们的孩子终有一天将统治这一切
and our child shall one day rule them all.
她冲着您来了
She's coming for you.
当然是冲着我来
Of course she is.
就让大门开着
Keep the gates open.
如果她想占领城堡
If she wants to take the castle, she'll have to murder
她得先屠杀成千上万无辜的人
thousands of innocent people first.
所谓“镣铐破除者”不过如此
So much for "the Breaker of Chains."
我们会攻克此城 女王陛下
We will storm the city, my queen.
我们会杀死您的敌人 杀死他们所有人
We will kill your enemies. All of them.
陛下
Your Grace.
我曾向您保证 假如我认为您犯了错误
I promised you I would look you in the eye and speak directly
我会直视您的眼睛并进献直言
if I ever thought you were making a mistake.
这是个错误
This is a mistake.
你看到我的孩子从空中坠落
You saw my child fall from the sky.
他们还抓走了弥桑黛
They took Missandei.
瑟曦必须被摧毁
Cersei needs to be destroyed,
但如果我们让龙和无垢者还有多斯拉克人
but if we attack King's Landing with Drogon and the Unsullied
进攻君临
and the Dothraki,
上万无辜的人会死去
tens of thousands of innocents will die.
这就是瑟曦带他们进入红堡的原因
That is why Cersei is bringing them into the Red Keep.
你来到这里就是为了保护这些民众啊
These are the people you came here to protect.
我求您 陛下
I beg you, Your Grace.
不要毁了这座您想要拯救的城市
Do not destroy the city you came to save.
不要变成您一直努力打败的敌人
Do not become what you have always struggled to defeat.
瓦里斯大人 你相信我们来到这里是有原因的吗
Do you believe we're here for a reason, Lord Varys?
我来到这里 是为了从暴君手中解放这个世界
I'm here to free the world from tyrants.
这是我的宿命
That is my destiny...
我会忠于我命 不计代价
and I will serve it, no matter the cost.
琼恩和盟军可能要两星期
It could be a fortnight before Jon and the allied armies
才能到达君临
make it to King's Landing.
与此同时 要求瑟曦投降
In the meantime, demand Cersei surrender.
让她用王位换她的命
Offer her her life in exchange for the throne.
如果有一线机会能避免屠杀
If there's a chance to avoid the coming slaughter,
我们就应该为之努力
we should make the effort.
与瑟曦对话阻止不了屠杀
Speaking to Cersei will not prevent a slaughter.
但或许让人们看清楚也好
But perhaps it's good the people see
“风暴降生”丹妮莉丝做了所有避免民众流血的努力
that Daenerys Stormborn made every effort to avoid bloodshed,
但瑟曦·兰尼斯特拒绝了
and Cersei Lannister refused.
当天罚降临时
They should know whom to blame
他们该知道谁才是罪魁祸首
when the sky falls down upon them.
我大半辈子都在辅佐暴君
I've served tyrants most of my life.
他们都爱说宿命
They all talk about destiny.
这个女孩带着三块石头走进火中
She's a girl who walked into a fire with three stones
然后带着三条龙出来了
and walked out with three dragons.
她怎么能不相信宿命？
How could she not believe in destiny?
也许这就是问题所在
Perhaps that's the problem.
她的经历使她相信
Her life has convinced her
她是命运派来拯救我们的
that she was sent here to save us all.
你又怎么知道她不是呢？
And how do you know she wasn't?
那我们就要聊聊琼恩·雪诺的问题了
Then there's the problem of Jon Snow.
也许他实际上才是答案
Perhaps it's actually a solution.
他们俩你都了解
You know them both.
告诉我 你觉得谁会是更好的统治者？
Tell me, who do you think would make a better ruler?
他不想要王位
He doesn't want the throne.
因此他才臣服
That's why he bent the knee.
你有没有想过 最好的统治者
Have you considered the best ruler
可能恰恰是不想统治的人？
might be someone who doesn't want to rule?
我们在讨论叛国
We're discussing treason.
不要假装你没有想过
Don't pretend you haven't thought about it.
我当然想过 光想想又不算叛国
Of course I've thought about it. Thoughts aren't treason.
他温和 又有分寸 而且是个男人
He's temperate and measured. He's a man,
这会让他更对维斯特洛领主们的胃口
which makes him more appealing to the lords of Westeros,
而我们需要他们的支持
whose support we are going to need.
乔佛里也是男人
Joffrey was a man.
我不觉得有鸡巴就真有资格
I don't think a cock is a true qualification,
我相信你也会同意
as I'm sure you'd agree.
他是王位的继承人
And he's the heir to the throne.
没错 因为他是个男人 恐怕鸡巴确实是重要的
Yes, because he's a man. Cocks are important, I'm afraid.
那我之前的提议呢？
What about my earlier proposal?
他们可以共同统治 作为国王和女王
They could rule together as king and queen.
她太强势
She's too strong for him.
她会迫使他服从她的意志 正如她所做的
She'd bend him to her will, as she already has.
他可以缓和她糟糕的冲动
He could temper her worst impulses.
正如你所做的？
As you have?
你喝了不少了
You're drinking quite a lot.
一个坦格利安父亲和一个史塔克母亲
A Targaryen father and a Stark mother.
琼恩是唯一有可能
Jon's the one man alive who might actually be able
让北境继续留在七国之内的人了
to keep the North in the Seven Kingdoms.
你效忠过多少个国王或女王？
How many kings and queens have you served?
五个？六个？我都数不过来了
Five? Six? I've lost count.
- 你一直都知道我的理由 - 在某一时刻
- You've always known my reasons. - At a certain point,
你选择一个你相信的人
you choose a person you believe in,
然后你为之战斗
and you fight for that person.
哪怕你知道这是一个错误？
Even if you know it's a mistake?
我相信我们的女王
I believe in our queen.
她会做出正确的选择
She'll make the right choice.
由她忠诚的谋臣辅佐
With the help of her loyal advisors.
你知道我的忠心所向
You know where my loyalty stands.
你知道我永远不会背叛国家
You know I will never betray the realm.
什么是国家？
What is the realm?
一个广阔的大陆 几百万人的家
A vast continent, home to millions of people,
这几百万人中 大多数并不在乎谁坐在铁王座上
most of whom don't care who sits on the Iron Throne.
假如错误的人坐上王座
Millions of people, many of whom will die
这几百万人中 许多人会死去
if the wrong person sits on that throne.
我们不知道他们的名字
We don't know their names,
但他们就像你和我一样真实存在
but they're just as real as you and I.
他们有活着的权利
They deserve to live.
他们应该能够喂养他们的孩子
They deserve food for their children.
我将以他们的利益为重 而不计个人的得失
I will act in their interest, no matter the personal cost.
那 她身上会发生什么？
So, what happens to her?
拜托
Please.
不要
Don't.
我已经尽可能坦诚了
I've spoken as honestly as I can.
我们每个人都有一个选择要做
Each of us has a choice to make.
我祈祷我们都能明智
I pray we choose wisely.
……她的其他顾问也一样
...as are the rest of her advisors.
发生什么了？
What happened?
攸伦·葛雷乔伊伏击了丹妮莉丝女王以及她的舰队
Euron Greyjoy ambushed Queen Daenerys and her fleet.
一头龙被杀 几艘舰船被击沉
One of the dragons was killed, several ships destroyed,
弥桑黛被俘
Missandei captured.
我一直希望着能亲眼目睹他们处决你的姐姐
I always wanted to be there when they execute your sister.
看来我是没这个机会了
Seems like I won't get the chance.
他们打算毁掉那座城市
They're going to destroy that city.
你知道他们会的
You know they will.
你打仗的时候逃跑过吗？
Have you ever run away from a fight?
你不像是你姐姐那种人 你不是
You're not like your sister. You're not.
你人比她好多了
You're better than she is.
你是一个好人 而你救不了她
You're a good man and you can't save her.
你没必要和她一起死
You don't need to die with her.
留下来
Stay here.
留下来和我在一起
Stay with me.
求你了
Please.
留下来吧
Stay.
你认为我是个好人？
You think I'm a good man?
为了瑟曦
I pushed a boy out a tower window,
我把一个男孩从塔楼的窗边推下去
crippled him for life
致使他终身残疾
for Cersei.
我亲手勒死了自己的堂弟
I strangled my cousin with my own hands
只是为了能回到瑟曦身边
just to get back to Cersei.
为了瑟曦
I would have murdered
我情愿杀死奔流城里的
every man, woman and child in Riverrun
每一个男女老少
for Cersei.
她面目可憎
She's hateful.
我又何尝不是
And so am I.
格雷果·克里冈
“魔山”
大人
My lord.
丹妮莉丝女王要求瑟曦无条件投降
Queen Daenerys demands Cersei's unconditional surrender
并立即释放纳斯岛的弥桑黛
and the immediate release of Missandei of Naath.
瑟曦女王要求丹妮莉丝无条件投降
Queen Cersei demands Daenerys's unconditional surrender.
若她拒不从命 纳斯岛的弥桑黛将会被就地正法
If she refuses, Missandei of Naath will die here and now.
科本……
Qyburn...
你是个理智的人
you're a rational man.
大人 我也是这样自夸的
Or so I flatter myself, my lord.
我们今日在此有这么一个机会
We have a chance here,
也许是我们最后一次机会来阻止一场杀戮
perhaps our last chance, to avoid carnage.
没错
Yes.
帮帮我
Help me.
我不忍心看见这城市陷入火海
I don't want to see this city burn.
我不忍心听见孩子们被活活烧死时发出的惨叫
I don't want to hear the screams of children burning alive.
是啊 那的确不是什么悦耳的声音
No, it is not a pleasant sound.
我——我不想听到那声音
I-- I don't want to hear it.
帮我拯救这座城市
Help me save this city.
大人 我只是我们女王的喉舌而已
My lord, I am only a mouthpiece for our queen.
你们女王
Your queen.
瑟曦是七大王国的女王
Cersei is Queen of the Seven Kingdoms.
而你是她的臣民
You are her subject.
她的统治已终结
Her reign is over.
你明白这一点 你也让她看清这一点
You understand this. Help her understand it.
对于你说的这种事我们一无所知
We understand nothing of the sort.
你们女王的最后一条龙不堪一击
Your queen's last dragon is vulnerable.
你们的军队疲惫倦怠 还有些厌战
Your armies are battle-weary and depleted,
而我们的军队则有黄金团的有力增援——
while ours have been reinforced with the Golden Compan--
准备！
Ready!
搭箭！
Nock!
拉弓！
Draw!
我知道你不在乎你的人民
I know you don't care about your people.
你为什么要在乎他们呢？
Why should you?
你们彼此憎恶
They hate you and you hate them.
但你不是一个怪物
But you're not a monster.
我明白这一点
I know this.
我曾亲眼目睹过 所以我明白这一点
I know this because I've seen it.
你曾经一直深爱着自己的孩子
You've always loved your children.
胜过爱自己
More than yourself,
胜过爱詹姆
more than Jaime...
胜过这世间一切
more than anything.
我求你
I beg you.
如果不是为你自己 这也是为你的孩子着想
If not for yourself, then for your child.
你的统治已终结
Your reign is over,
但这并不意味着你的生命必须结束
but that doesn't mean your life has to end.
这并不意味着你的孩子必须死
It doesn't mean your baby has to die.
如果你还有什么遗言 现在就说
If you have any last words, now is the time.
龙焰
Dracarys.
不
No.
衣柜字幕组出品
冰火中文维基：http://asoiaf.huijiwiki.com/
本集关键字：史塔克家族 雷哥
《权力的游戏》下集预告